Lorenzo Javier Colodro

Full Stack Developer

javiercolodro@gmail.com 🐛 +54 9358 4392425 👂 Córdoba -Argentina 🕥 Github 🛗 Linked In 🔗 Portfolio

ABOUT ME

My experience in aviation has been a significant part of my personal and professional growth for 5 years. In this new stage in programming, I am excited to apply the skills I acquired through an intensive JavaScript Bootcamp. My challenge is to provide valuable contributions to any project I am involved in and meet the needs of the company.

I aim to transition my career and aspirations into the technology sector, combining my programming knowledge with my passion for delivering an excellent customer service.

PROJECTS

Backend Developer - Klowhub - Hackathon

11/2024 - 12/2024

- International Hackathon No Country Organization (5 weeks of development)
- Developed an application that enables users to create projects, purchase courses, and access educational resources, fostering a collaborative learning ecosystem.
- Built a Courses microservice, integrating Cloudinary for video, image, and document management.
- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs to handle course creation, reading, updating, and deletion (CRUD operations).

Backend Stack: Nest.js, TypeScript, TypeORM, PostgreSQL, Cloudinary, Multer, Docker.

FullStack Developer - Comunidad Perros&Gatos APP

09/2024 - 11/2024

- International Collaborative Project No Country Organization (5 weeks of development)
- Developed an MVP application allowing users to register and apply for pet adoptions, with a focus on connecting potential adopters to pets in shelters.

Frontend Stack: React Vite, React-Router-Dom, MaterialUi, CSS, Js-cookie.

Backend Stack: Node.js, TypeScript, Prisma, Google Oauth, Express-session, Passport, Cloudinary, Node Mailer, Multer, Docker, PostgreSQL Render Database, Table Plus, Swagger.

FullStack Developer - My Favourites Videos APP

08/2024 - 10/2024

- Personal Project (2 months of development)
- Developed a Video Gallery application with both backend and frontend components, enabling users to store their favourite videos and manage personal video preferences.

Frontend Stack: React Vite, TypeScript, Redux, Tailwind CSS, Axios, React-Router-Dom, Toastify, Lite-youtube, Heroicons. Backend Stack: Node. js, TypeScript, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Sequelize-Cli, Bcryptjs, Node Mailer, Jsonwebtoken.

Agile Methodologies: Experience with Scrum, using tools like Trello for task management, and participating in daily stand-ups to review progress, address challenges, and align daily goals.

Explore additional projects ∂

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML | CSS | SASS | JAVASCRIPT | REACT | REACT ROUTER DOM | NODEJS | EXPRESS | NEST | TYPESCRIPT | POSTGRESQL | SEQUELIZE | PRISMA | TYPEORM | REDUX | BOOTSTRÁP | GITHUB | POSTMAN | TAILWIND | JEST | SUPERTEST | CYPRESS | CLOUDINARY | NODEMAILER | RESEND | DOCKER | TABLE PLUS | SWAGGER | TOASTIFY | RENDER | JOI | SOONER | JSONWEBTOKEN | BCRIPTJS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Support in Call Center

11/2021 - 12/2022

- Managing and responding to 30-40 phone calls, chats, and emails daily to ensure optimal customer assistance.
- Providing support and assistance to customers across 34 states in the United States and Central America.

Cabin Crew 10/2014 - 01/2021

- I was responsible for the safety and excellent service to customers on 23 domestic flights and 22 international destinations.
- I had the opportunity to supervise 10 regional flights for junior crew members and achieve improved performance.

EDUCATION

JavaScript Bootcamp on Plataforma 5

09/2023

- +1000 hours of coding
- 9 AM to 7 PM schedule
- 7 months intensive
- Pair-programming activities
- Agile methodologies: Scrum, Planning, Daily Stand-up, Review, Demo, and Trello.

LANGUAGES

- Spanish Native
- English C1